Guide to the Dan Nimrod papers, 1938-2002 MS2192
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dan Nimrod papers
1938-2002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2192
27.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains correspondence, publications, newspaper clippings, speeches, legal documents, photographs, audiotapes, and videotapes. The material dates from ca. 1950-2002, although the bulk is from 1977-2002. They are the papers of Jacob Dan Nimrod, largely from the time he resumed his writing career in 1977 until his death in 2002. The material in the collection covers the wide range of Nimrod's political writing activities, mainly concerning Israeli politics and foreign relations. Other prominent topics include apartheid in South Africa and the civil war in Nicaragua. It also includes the writings he saved of some of his correspondents.
Box UP21
Box UP22
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
In 2000, Nimrod donated his library of over 2,500 volumes and his extensive archives to The George Washington University.
Biographical Note
Jacob Dan Nimrod (1923-2002) was a Polish-Israeli-Canadian political commentator, active in various Zionist causes.
Born in what is today the Ukraine (then part of Poland) in 1923, Dan Nimrod, originally named Ya'acov Hebel, was active in the Zionist movement from a young age. At age 15, he migrated across Europe on foot to reach what was then British Mandatory Palestine.
At the outbreak of World War II, Nimrod enlisted in the British Army's Jewish Palestinian Unit and served in North Africa. He successfully defended himself against desertion charges, which arose when he joined the Irgun Zvai Leumi (National Military Organization). In 1944, Irgun began fighting British authorities for the creation of a Jewish state in Palestine. At war's end, Nimrod served as Irgun's commander in several European countries, joining its general staff in 1947. He also directed the organization's public information service in Eastern Europe and worked to acquire weapons in France.
On May 14, 1948, Israel officially declared its independence. Almost immediately, several surrounding Arab countries attacked. Nimrod fought in the subsequent war (1948-49) while continuing his work to supply the Jewish State with weapons from Europe. After the war ended, Nimrod served on the central committee for the Israeli nationalist party Herut (which later formed part of the Likud Party) and was an unsuccessful candidate for the Knesset (the Israeli parliament). In 1949, Nimrod married his first wife, Esther Grachanek, who later passed away from natural causes. During the early 1950s, Nimrod remained active in Israeli politics, regularly penning columns under the name Ya'acov Lotan.
In 1956, Nimrod emigrated to Canada. He initially settled in Newfoundland, but later moved to Montreal. He initially served as a principal at a Jewish school but later became an independent teacher of Hebrew. Nimrod married Anita Affholter, originally from Switzerland, in 1961.
Nimrod resumed his writing career anew in 1977, after his old friend, Menachem Begin, was elected prime minister of Israel. He founded the Canadian Jewish Herald, a compendium of articles relating to Israeli politics, to counter what he saw as attacks on Begin and the Likud Party in other media.
Nimrod formed the self-financed Dawn Publishing Company as part of that effort in 1979. Over the next 23 years, he edited, authored, or compiled 62 books, newspapers, monographs, magazines, anthologies, position papers, and special dossiers, and corresponded with people around the world as part of his campaigns.
In 2000, Nimrod donated his library of over 2,500 volumes and his extensive archives to The George Washington University. He desired to present a "different perspective" on the Arab-Israeli conflict to researchers in the capital of the United States.
Nimrod died in Montreal on April 22, 2002.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence, publications, newspaper clippings, speeches, legal documents, photographs, audiotapes, and videotapes. The material dates from ca. 1950-2002, although the bulk is from 1977-2002. They are the papers of Jacob Dan Nimrod, largely from the time he resumed his writing career in 1977 until his death in 2002. The material in the collection covers the wide range of Nimrod's political writing activities, mainly concerning Israeli politics and foreign relations. Other prominent topics include apartheid in South Africa and the civil war in Nicaragua. It also includes the writings he saved of some of his correspondents.
Nimrod's estate donated the material to The George Washington University following Nimrod's death in 2002. The correspondence is arranged by the country of the correspondent. Within each correspondence series, it is arranged in alphabetical order by individual correspondent or organization, except for general folders such as "Special Interest" and "Organizations." Within each folder, the correspondence is sorted chronologically. Nimrod's estate also included cross-references in many of the folders.
The collection also contains the papers of Sol Modell, a frequent correspondent of Nimrod's and a former professor of history at Los Angeles Valley College. Upon Modell's death, his family donated the papers to Florida Atlantic University in Boca Raton, Florida, where Modell had retired. The university transferred them to Nimrod, who included them with his papers donated to The George Washington University.
Collection Organization
Organized into 12 series: Correspondence - Israel; Correspondence - Canada; Correspondence - Germany; Correspondence - United Kingdom; Correspondence - United States; Correspondence - Other Countries; Biographical Information - Prominent Correspondents; Publications, Book Reviews and Promotional Materials; Biographical Information - Nimrod; Sol Modell, papers; Ephemera.
Israel; Zionists -- Correspondence; Photographs; Israel -- History; Israel-Palestinian conflict; Israel -- Politics and government; Israel -- Foreign policy; Arab-Israel conflict; Irgun tsevai leumi; Videotapes; South Africa; Zionists; Zionism; Apartheid; United States; Montréal (Québec); Jewish-Arab relations; Audiotapes; Canada; Modell, Solomon; Horwin, Leonard; Dawn Publishing Company; Nimrod, Dan
- Correspondence - Israel, 1977-2002; MS2192 Series 1; 3 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains Nimrod's correspondence with people and organizations in Israel, mostly activists. It includes letters between him and prominent government officials, including former Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. The bulk of the material dates from 1977-2002. Some of the material in this series is in Hebrew. This series is organized by correspondent's last name or organization name, then chronologically within each folder. Folders labeled "Special Interest" and "Organizations" contain multiple correspondents, sorted alphabetically within those folders.
  - Abelson, Meir 1986-1989, 10/23/1986-12/25/1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abelson, Meir 1990-1991, 01/26/1990-11/20/1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abelson, Meir 1992-2001 & undated material, 02/14/1992-12/04/2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abir, Mordechai (prof), 05/10/1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abrams, Kevin E., 06/17/1996-09/13/1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Achimeir, Yosef, 07/02/1980-02/02/1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Akzin, Benjamin (prof), 08/06/1979-06/18/1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alfandari, Mordechai, 05/27/1986-02/15/1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alpert, Carl, 09/10/1982-05/22/2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alster, Joseph, 03/10/1995-11/05/2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amiqam, Eliahu, 03/31/1985-07/14/1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Amrami, Joel, 01/09/1986-02/16/1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ariel, Municipal Council (Nachman, Ron), 10/15/1990-12/31/1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Autonomy Abolition Struggle Command, 10/17/1994-07/1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Balgur, Raphael (dr), 05/14/1988-04/21/2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bar-Ilan University, 04/25/1994-12/2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bar Itzhak, Shulamith, 02/28/1998-03/09/1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Barak, Ben Amos, 08/14/1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barak, Ehud, 11/1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barnea, Joseph, 12/18/1986-06/25/1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bendor, David, 05/11/1986-09/06/1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - B'eretz Yisrael (Joseph Kister), 06/03/1986-01/29/1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Besa Center for International Studies (Bar Elan University), 04/25/1994-12/22/2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Betar/Tagar - Ari Licht, 06/19/1992-03/20/1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Blech, Gemma, 01/14/1996-09/16/1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bloch, Michael S., 07/18/1991-02/09/1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Brill, Bruce & Vivian, 03/21/1981-07/27/1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brodetzki, Moshe, 11/20/1981-07/02/1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Carpi, Daniel (prof), 08/06/1979-02/26/2001 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cartman, Gerry (dr), 06/21/1982-12/10/1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Central Zionist Archives, 07/31/1988-04/26/1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Centre of Jewish Activism (Avraham Sheinman (director)), 02/12/1989-04/27/1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Centre for Information, Documentation and Communication (UVDA), 01/1990-11/13/1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Christian Friends of Israel, 10/05/1993-12/22/1998 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Edwards, R.K. (dr) 1977-1985, 05/30/1977-08/27/1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Eidelberg, Paul (dr/prof) 1979, 02/11/1979-12/31/1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Eidelberg, Paul (dr/prof) 1980-1996, 01/20/1980-01/29/1996 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Eidelberg, Paul (dr/prof) Manuscript - a Judaic Constitution to prevent tyranny, 06/29/1995-07/18/1995 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Eidelberg Case, 04/22/1980-03/24/1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Eliav, Yaacov, 08/06/1984-03/31/1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Eliysha (Elyakim Ha'etzni esq.) 1986-Aug. 1987, 05/24/1986-08/28/1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Eliysha (Elyakim Ha'etzni esq.) Sept.-Dec. 1987, 09/04/1987-12/27/1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Eliysha (Elyakim Ha'etzni esq.) 1988, 02/12/1988-12/12/1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Eliysha (Elyakim Ha'etzni esq.) Jan.-Mar. 1989, 01/08/1989-03/31/1989 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Eliysha (Elyakim Ha'etzni esq.) Apr.-Dec. 1989, 04/02/1989-12/31/1989 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Eliysha (Elyakim Ha'etzni esq.) 1990-1991, 01/03/1990-08/26/1991 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Eris, Avraham, 06/28/1983-07/28/1986 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Ettinger, Yoram, 10/08/1995-03/12/1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Falk, Avner (dr), 12/24/1997-03/04/1998 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Fisch, Harold (dr/prof), 01/11/1978-07/21/2000 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Fishler, Ben Zion, 08/16/1981-11/02/1989 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Foreign Ministry Embassies & Consulates, 1979-1993 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    General note
    [from contents page in folder:] Moshe Dayan, Foreign Minister; Yitzhak Eldan, Min. Plenipotentiary; Foreign Ministry, Israel; Hon. Yitzhak Mayer, Ambassador, Embassy of Israel, Belgium; Hon. [Benjamin] Netanyahu, Ambassador, United Nations; Yitzhak Oren, Consulate General of Israel, New York; Hon. Gideon Tadmor, Ambassador, Embassy of Israel, Lima
  - Foreign Ministry of Israel (Yegar, Moshe (dr) & Shmorak, Dov (dr)), 11/08/1981-01/15/1986 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Gefen Publishing House Ltd., 09/14/1999-10/26/2000 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Golan, Zev, 08/10/1986-07/07/2000 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Goldstein, Irwin, 04/12/1995-03/04/1997 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Government of Israel, 1978-1992 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    [from contents page in folder:] Shulamit Aloni, Minister of Education and Culture; Moshe Arens, Minister of Defence; Zewulun Hammer, MK, Ministry of Education; Y. Kadishai, Director, Prime Minister's Office; Yossi Olmert, Director, Government Press Office; Shimon Peres, Prime Minister; Yitzhak Shamir, Prime Minister; Ariel Sharon, MK, Minister of Defence; Shmuel Tamir, Minister of Justice [folder originally titled Foreign Minister's Office, relabeled to reflect contents]
  - Government of Israel (Olmert, Yossi), 03/13/1990-12/27/1990 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Grauman, M., 06/23/1980-01/05/1982 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Green, Elliott, 03/02/1979-06/21/1989 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Ha'etzni, Elyakim esq. 1992-1994, 03/24/1992-02/12/1994 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Ha'etzni, Elyakim esq. 1998-2002, 07/26/1998-02/21/2002 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Hatehiya Movement, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Ha-ummah (Joseph Chrust), 09/30/1992-05/18/2000 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Hebrew University, 05/31/1978-11/21/1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Hebron, Jewish Community of, 06/03/1986-09/16/1987 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Hecht, Rubin (dr), 12/22/1978-05/13/1993 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Horizons East - Israel Tal, 01/20/1986-01/17/1992 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Herut Hatzohar World - Zionist Revisionist, 10/05/1977-09/24/1993 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Hurwitz, Harry, 05/10/1978-01/06/1987 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Inside Israel, 02/26/1996-04/05/1996 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Institute for Advanced Strategic & Political Studies - Loewenberg, Robert (prof), 05/28/1986-03/28/1995 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Institute for Zionist Research, Tel Aviv University, 11/1980-06/23/1981 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - International Christian Embassy Jerusalem, 02/23/1982-07/11/1992 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - International Coalition for missing Israeli Soldiers (ICMIS), 1994-04/27/1995 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Israel Public Policy Institute, 02/15/1984-08/09/1984 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Israel Torah Foundation (ITF) - Lerner, Yoel, 03/30/1987-11/23/1988 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Jabotinski Institute, Tel Aviv, 04/13/1987-12/04/1998 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Jerusalem Institute for Western Defense - Ramati, Yohanan, 07/06/1987-06/23/2000 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Jerusalem Post, The, 08/02/1977-08/28/2000 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Jerusalem Temple Foundation - Stanley Goldfoot - 1986, 01/26/1986-12/19/1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jerusalem Temple Foundation - Stanley Goldfoot - 1987, 01/04/1987-12/22/1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jerusalem Temple Foundation - Stanley Goldfoot - 1988-1990, 01/03/1988-10/14/1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jerusalem Temple Foundation - Stanley Goldfoot 1991-1999, 10/05/1991-05/05/1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jewish National Library & University, 01/25/1978-12/31/1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jordan [in] is Arab Palestine (JIP), 09/22/1981-08/05/1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kahane, Meir, 02/13/1983-10/28/1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Kanzler, S., 1984-03/09/1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Katz, Shmuel, 03/17/1985-04/30/2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Knesset members, 1982-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    [from contents page of folder:] Eliyahu Ben Elisar, Dr., Chairman, Foreign Affairs & Defence; Rabbi Chaim Druckman; Dr. Uzi Landau; David Magen; Prof. Yoseph Rom; Menahem Savidor, Speaker of the Knesset; Dov Shilansky, Deputy Minister; Yoash Tsiddon-Chatto
  - Kosoff, Barbara, 10/10/1983-03/24/1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lang, Bob - Realities EMUNIN, 10/03/1991-06/04/1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Lax, Paul (dr), 06/04/1981-12/12/1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lerner, Aaron (dr), 08/02/1994-08/03/1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Leshem, Moshe (Colonel) (Ret.), 09/07/2000-10/17/2000 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lev-ami, Shlomo (dr), 07/06/1987-12/18/1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Levi, Ruth, 08/04/1987-03/30/1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lottner, Pircha, 07/28/1984-08/13/1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - MAARIV evening paper - Samuel Shnitzer, Editor, 11/20/1980-03/27/1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Machon Shiloach Institute, 08/04/1978-02/10/1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Maimon, Rav Library - Central Library of Judaica, 08/29/1995-07/10/2000 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Mattan, E. (dr), 01/11/1987-12/15/1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Medad, Yisrael, 05/04/1983-10/14/1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Mirelman, Jose (dr), 06/04/1979-03/16/1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Moledet - Hersh, Shlomo, 07/20/1992-04/20/1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - More, Hadassah, 09/02/1985-09/21/1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Moriel, Ruth & Menachem, 05/08/1980-12/17/1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Nansen Institute, the - Simons Chaim (rabbi/dr), 04/03/1978-07/01/1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - National Circle, the - Shem-ur, Ora, 08/12/1984-07/01/1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Nativ, the 1990-Jun 1992, 12/11/1990-06/25/1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Nativ, the Jul. 1992, 07/02/1992-07/24/1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Nativ, the Aug. 1992-Dec. 1992, 08/03/1992-12/06/1992 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Nativ, the 1993-2000, 01/07/1993-08/28/2000 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Nedava, Joseph (prof/dr) 1979-1981, 03/14/1979-12/29/1981 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Nedava, Joseph (prof/dr) 1982-1987, 02/14/1982-10/19/1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Ne'eman, Yuval, 01/08/1980-05/07/1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Nekuda, 05/09/1991-03/24/1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Neve Shalom, 12/01/1982-01/31/1985 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Newsview - Perry, Victor, 08/20/1982-05/06/1983 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Nir College of Judaic Studies - Cooperberg, Gary, 09/21/1987-11/09/1992 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Nir, Michael, 02/12/1997-03/19/1997 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Nisan, Mordechai (prof) 1979-1981, 08/14/1979-12/30/1981 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Nisan, Mordechai (prof) 1982, 01/01/1982-12/29/1982 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Nisan, Mordechai (prof) 1983-1987, 01/10/1983-11/04/1987 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Nisan, Mordechai (prof) 1988-1991, 03/27/1988-12/30/1991 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Nisan, Mordechai (prof) 1992-2002, 01/05/1992-03/26/2002 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Oberman, Barbara, 05/10/1978-02/26/1982 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - One Israel/Israel Community Development Foundation - pro Yesha Hasbarah, 07/27/1994-10/14/1994 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Organizations, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    [from contents page of folder:] Bet Hagudim; First International Conference and Festival of Jewish Theatre; Jewish Agency for Israel; Movement to Stop the Withdrawal from Sinai; Youth Aliyah
  - Peace Watch, 05/30/1995-06/18/1995 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Pinner, Daniel, 03/13/1989-05/07/1997 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Prime Minister's Office, 10/07/1977-05/29/2000 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Rabinowitz, L.I. (rabbi/dr), 09/21/1978-01/08/1982 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Rackman, Emanuel (rabbi), 01/08/1981-12/20/2000 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Ramati, Yohanan & Shoul, 05/18/1986-06/23/2000 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Seckbach, Fern, 05/05/1992-01/13/1993 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Seligman, M., 06/06/1979-05/04/1981 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Shalem Centre, the (National Policy Institute - Dr. Yoram Hazoni), 1995-01/31/1996 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Shapiro, Jay, 07/16/1980-06/13/2000 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Sharon, Moshe (dr/prof), 02/19/1981-09/05/1986 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Shulewitz, Malka, 03/15/1982-02/14/2001 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Special Interests, 1978-2000 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    [from contents page of folder:] Arbel, E.; Ariev; Ascent Quarterly; Association of Americans & Canadians in Israel; Azimov, Dan; Ben-Chaim, Reuven; Ben Eliezer, Judith; Bilich, Zeev (dr); Cohen, Moshe David; Collins, Yehudit; Counterpoint; Cranko, Tim; Dan, Uri; Deckelbaum, David; Drori, Moshe; Dwek, David; Echmeir, Joseph; Flansberg, Gerald; Friedman, Yehoshua; Gallin, Aryeh; Golan Residents Committee; Grossman, Judy; Haya; Heimowitz, D.; Horowitz, Danny; Israel News Bulletin; Jabotinsky, Ze'ev; Jonathan Institute, the; Katz, Shmuel; Kaufman, Shmuel; King, Alexander; Kotlowitz, Raphael (dr); Korothe, Baruch; Lehman, Emil (dr); Loshitzky, Yosefa (dr); Meir, Yitzhak; Minc, Thelma; Nakdimon, Shlomo; Ofek, Bina & Uriel; N.R.; Padwa, Jack; Pearlman, Ze'ev (dr); Perlmutter, Wayne; Raymist, Malkah; Rogan, Barbara; Rubin, Jabotinsky, Karni; Rubinoff, David; Schneider, Ludwig; Schrieber, David; Schwartz, Michel S.; Sheinman, Avraham; Shelanski, Dov; Silver, Nathan; Steimatski, Eric; Steinberg, David; Sussman, Shai; Tavin, Eli; Taussig, Bunem Joel (rabbi); Slowes, S.; Tura Perez; Turecki, S.; Turetzky, Shmuel; Wigdor, Phil; WOJAC; Zimerman, Reuben; Zohar, Ezra (prof); Zunnenshine, Irvin
  - Spiro, S. (rabbi/dr), 03/06/1978-08/11/2000 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Sunshine, Herbert (rabbi/attorney), 10/15/1991-09/15/1995 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Sussman, Jeff, 01/11/1983-08/24/1984 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Tel Aviv University (Rosenthal, Aviva), 04/15/1999-06/16/1999 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Tsomet-Israel - Sherman, Martin, 12/03/1981-01/23/1992 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Tzachor, Haviva, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - University of Haifa, 03/31/1994-12/11/1995 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Vickers, Sylvia Souster, 07/29/1986-02/20/1991 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Victims of Arab Terror (VAT) - Hoffman, Shifra, 04/25/1979-10/08/1992 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Wallis, Nigel, 07/19/1990-10/29/1990 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Women in Green Matar, 1994-2000 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - World Zionist Organization, 07/10/1979-12/26/1999 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Yad Vashem, 08/21/1991-11/29/1991 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Yesha (Judea Samaria & Gaza International Relations), 07/31/1991-02/20/2001 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Yeshrun, Shraga (prof), 08/24/1987-10/12/1987 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Yinon, Odet, 11/05/1981-11/22/1988 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Youth & Hechalutz Department - Joint Authority for Jewish Education - Chairman Shlomo Gravetz, 08/17/1993-07/30/1995 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Correspondence - Canada, 1977-2002; MS2192 Series 2; 3 Linear feet
  This series contains Nimrod's correspondence with people and organizations in Canada. The bulk of the material dates from 1977-2002. Some of the material is in French. It includes Dan and Anita Nimrod's papers from their campaign to gain official recognition for Israel's Magen David Adom from the International Committee of the Red Cross. Most of the other material is Nimrod's correspondence. It also contains Nimrod's letters to the editor, open letters, "Dear Friends" letters, and "Dear Reader" letters. This series is organized by correspondent's last name or organization name, then chronologically within each folder. Folders labeled "Special Interest," "Media-General," "Media-Jewish," and "Organizations" contain multiple correspondents.
  - Allied Jewish Community Services, 11/28/1977-05/04/1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Archives & Libraries - Jewish, 1978-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    [from contents page of folder:] Canadian Jewish Congress Archives; Jewish Historical Society of Canada; Jewish Institute of Higher Research, C.R.S. of C.; Jewish Public Library
  - Association of Jewish Libraries (Ontario Chapter), 03/01/1995-06/05/2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Azrieli, David J., 09/19/1983-07/07/2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Baker, Marc, 02/16/1995-08/18/2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Benyair, Shaltiel, 07/30/1983-11/13/1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bernick, Allen, 04/28/1980-11/27/1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Betar/Tagar, 03/01/1980-10/04/1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bilek, William (dr), 03/31/1982-04/22/1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Blank, David, 01/20/1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - B'nai B'rith - Canada, 05/1994-07/07/2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cameron, Neil (prof), 12/17/1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Canada Israel Committee (C.I.C.), 10/05/1979-11/04/1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Academic Foundation for Peace in the Middle East (C.A.F.P.), 04/26/1979-04/01/1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cdn. Broadcasting Corporation (C.B.C.), 11/11/1996-01/23/1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cdn. Friends of Bar-Ilan University, 05/03/1982-11/17/2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cdn. Holocaust Remembrance Association, 06/23/1993-02/02/1996 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cdn. Institute for Jewish Research (C.I.J.R.), 01/10/1991-05/24/1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cdn. Jewish Congress (C.J.C.), 10/11/1977-02/12/1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cdn. Jewish Herald, 08/10/1994-03/21/2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cdn. Jewish News, 01/23/1978-08/28/2000 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cdn. Zionist Federation, 03/23/1978-08/18/1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Carr, Donald, 09/07/1984-01/27/1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Charness, Gerald N.F., 06/20/1979-03/14/1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)